Linfang Zheng

1088 Xueyuan Avenue, Shenzhen 518055, P.R. China | +86-186-4655-1986 | zhenglinfang@icloud.com

Profile

A highly motivated Ph.D. researcher specialises in computer vision, deep learning, and robotics, with expertise in visual 6D object pose estimation and tracking. Demonstrates a strong aptitude for quickly comprehending complex concepts and exhibits excellent collaboration and problem-solving skills.

Education

Ph.D. in University of Birmingham (UoB)

01/2020 - Expected Graduation: 07/2024

Computer Science | Supervisors: Aleš Leonardis, Hyungjin Chang

Ph.D. in Southern University of Science and Technology (SUSTech) 04/2021 - 04/2024

Visiting Student | Control and Learning for Robotics and Autonomy (CLEAR) Lab | Supervisor: Wei Zhang

Master in Harbin Institute of Technology (HIT)

08/2015 - 07/2017

Integrated Circuit Engineering | Outstanding Master's Graduate

Bachelor in Harbin Institute of Technology (HIT)

08/2011 - 07/2015

Electronic Information Science and Technology | Direct Admission to Graduate School

Research Experience

Category-level Articulated Object Pose Estimation | UoB

01/2024 - 03/2024

· Submitted to ECCV 2024 (co-author). Under review.

Cloth Pushing via Trajectory and Contact Pose Optimisation | SUSTech

12/2023 - 03/2024

· Submitted to IROS 2024 (co-author). Under review.

Category-level 6D Object Pose Refinement | UoB & SUSTech

03/2023 - 11/2023

- · Developed an object pose refinement algorithm, resolving challenges in geometric discrepancies among category-level objects.
- · Significantly enhanced category-level object pose estimation performance, surpassing current state-of-theart methods with substantial performance advantages.
- · Accepted by **CVPR 2024** (first author).
- · Paper: GeoReF: Geometric Alignment Across Shape Variation for Category-level Object Pose Refinement

Visual Planar Region Extraction for Uneven Terrains | SUSTech

11/2022 - 09/2023

- · Collaboratively Introduced a multi-resolution planer region extraction strategy for uneven terrains from point cloud data. Contributed to designing deep learning-based plane segmentation.
- · Accepted by ICRA 2024 (co-author).
- · Paper: Multi-Resolution Planar Region Extraction for Uneven Terrains

Category-level Object Pose Estimation | UoB & SUSTech

08/2022 - 05/2023

- Proposed a real-time and outlier-robust hybrid-scope feature extraction network, substantially enhancing category-level pose estimation performance, **notably enhancing the** 5°2**cm metric by 14.5%.**
- Introduced a network facilitating joint extraction of local-global geometric structure features, enhancing pose estimation for complex-shaped objects.
- · Published in CVPR 2023 (first author).

· Paper: <u>HS-Pose: Hybrid Scope Feature Extraction for Category-Level Object Pose Estimation</u>

3D Joint Gaze Estimation | UoB

01/2022 - 04/2023

- · Collaboratively introduced a cutting-edge depth-aware joint attention estimation framework, surpassing current benchmarks.
- · Addressed the previously unexplored problem of integrating a depth prior and a 3D joint field-of-view probability map to estimate attention targets in a scene.
- Published in CVPR Workshop 2023 (co-author).
- · Paper: Where are They Looking in 3D Space

Instance-level 6D Object Pose Tracking | UoB & SUSTech

02/2020 - 03/2022

- Introduced the first neural network-based prior pose generation scheme using object pose history to forecast future poses effectively.
- Developed a real-time temporally-primed pose estimation architecture, proficient in handling occlusions for textureless and symmetric objects.
- · Published in ICRA 2022 (first author).
- · Paper: TP-AE: Temporally Primed 6D Object Pose Tracking with Auto-Encoders

Instance-level Object Pose Estimation and Refinement | UoB

08/2022 - 03/2022

- · Collaboratively introduced a Transformer-based network, leveraging global feature correlation to enhance object pose estimation performance.
- Published in ECCV Workshop 2022 (co-author).

Paper: Trans6D: Transformer-Based 6D Object Pose Estimation and Refinement

Reinforcement Q-Learning for Switched Linear Systems | SUSTech

05/2019 - 12/2019

- · Collaboratively proposed an algorithm with a carefully designed parametric approximator that respects the analytical structure of the exact Q-function, paired with an associate parameter training algorithm.
- · Published in American Control Conference ACC 2020 (co-author).
- · Paper: Optimal Control Inspired Q-Learning for Switched Linear Systems

Work Experience

SUSTech | Prof. Wei Zhang's CLEAR Lab | Research Assistant

03/2019 - 01/2020

- · Assisted in project and research work including embedded software and hardware design, algorithm implementation, and project proposal writing.
- Participated in research on reinforcement learning based on optimal control, resulting in publication at ACC 2020.

DJI | Hardware Department | Embedded Hardware Engineer

07/2017 - 03/2019

- Evaluated the rationality of electronic component selection in the company's embedded hardware circuit design, enhancing design efficiency.
- Managed arrangements and follow-ups for electronic component performance verification, improving the stability of the electronic component supply chain.
- · Achieved cost savings for the company through optimised electronic component selection, receiving recognition and rewards.

Internship at DJI | RM Department | Embedded Hardware Engineer. 07/2016 - 09/2016

· Supported Robomasters competition field hardware circuit-related tasks and summer camp activities.

Awards

- · Outstanding Master's Graduate, HIT, China, 2017
- · Silver Award for Outstanding Master's Thesis, HIT, China, 2017
- · First Prize Scholarship, HIT, China, 2011-2017
- · Second Prize in the Technology Innovation and Entrepreneurship Training Program, HIT, China, 2014
- · Second Prize in the First Physics Academic Competition, HIT, China, 2014
- · Second Prize Scholarship, People's Daily (People.cn), China, 2014

Skills

- · Language: English (IELTS 6.5), Mandarin (Mother Language)
- · Programming Languages: Python, C, Verilog
- · Deep Learning: PyTorch, TensorFlow
- · Mandarin: Mother Language
- · Hardware Design: Embedded Hardware Design, Integrated Circuits, FPGA
- · Embedded Software Design